<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pen-y-Fan</title>
    <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pen-y-Fan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>:copyright: Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-SA 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 19:18:05 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pen-y-fan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My developer content recommendations</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/mm/dd/my-developer-content-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 19:18:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/mm/dd/my-developer-content-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>This is my curated and opinionated list on how I try to keep up to date with what&amp;rsquo;s going on in software development and in particular PHP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install NGINX Unit on WSL 2 (Ubuntu)</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/07/26/how-to-install-nginx-unit-on-wsl-2-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 22:13:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/07/26/how-to-install-nginx-unit-on-wsl-2-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to experiment with NGINX unit as it offers the ability to specify the runtime for the project, this will be particularly useful when some projects are PHP 7.4, some PHP 8.0 and others PHP 8.1. This guide explains how to install NGINX unit on Windows WSL 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 19:45:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a father, husband and geek.
I have always enjoyed coding. My interested started when my uncle bought me a ZX Spectrum 48k when I was only 11! I&amp;rsquo;m giving my age away there 😉.
From Oct 2015, I was an admin on the Real Racing 3 Wiki. This included updating the site, using HTML, Wiki mark-up and designing templates. This allowed editors to enter high-quality data and display it in a consistent layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating my Hexo blog to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/07/25/migrating-my-hexo-blog-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 18:52:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/07/25/migrating-my-hexo-blog-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post using Hugo static site generator, following the successful migration of my hexo site to Hugo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to send Emails using PHPMailer from Windows</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/09/14/How-to-send-Emails-using-PHPMailer-from-Windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 19:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/09/14/How-to-send-Emails-using-PHPMailer-from-Windows/</guid>
      <description>This is a basic tutorial on how to send emails from Windows using PHPMailer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install MySQL on WSL 2 (Ubuntu)</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/08/08/How-to-install-MySQL-on-WSL-2-Ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 16:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/08/08/How-to-install-MySQL-on-WSL-2-Ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>How to install and configure MySQL 8.0 on WSL 2 (Ubuntu), this guide assumes WSL 2 is already installed with Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set up VS Code to use PHP with Xdebug 3 on Windows</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/08/03/How-to-Set-up-VS-Code-to-use-PHP-with-Xdebug-3-on-Windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 22:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/08/03/How-to-Set-up-VS-Code-to-use-PHP-with-Xdebug-3-on-Windows/</guid>
      <description>VS Code with PHP and Xdebug 3 Xdebug 3 is an extremely powerful debugging tool for PHP. Although print_r(), var_dump() and dd() have their uses, Xdebug gives more powerful debugging options: step debugging allows the ability to view execution of each line of code, including the ability to view all variables and their values. Code coverage is useful to identify untested code, or code which is never executed (dead code).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standard setup for PHP projects 2021</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/05/23/Standard-setup-for-PHP-projects-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 08:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/05/23/Standard-setup-for-PHP-projects-2021/</guid>
      <description>The focus of this blog is to help set up PHP Projects in PhpStorm. I have also included snippets from my side-projects. I hope the information will be useful for other PHP projects. This is a follow-up to my blog Standard Setup for PHP projects from 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Docker</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/02/12/Troubleshooting-Docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 20:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/02/12/Troubleshooting-Docker/</guid>
      <description>I have been using Docker since I installed Pop!_OS On my laptop Oct 2020. I deliberately have not installed PHP, MySQL or Apache on my laptop, which has forced me to learn to use Docker! The first tutorial I followed was the Docker docs get started after I installed Docker. I found this to be a useful introduction, even though I wanted a PHP environment, the guide still explained the basics of Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up PhpStorm to use PHP with PHPUnit and xDebug in Docker</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/10/10/Set-up-PhpStorm-to-use-PHP-with-PHPUnit-and-xDebug-in-Docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 17:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/10/10/Set-up-PhpStorm-to-use-PHP-with-PHPUnit-and-xDebug-in-Docker/</guid>
      <description>I have recently configured my windows 10 laptop with an additional SSD, so I could experiment with Linux. I have already installed Pop!_OS Git, PhpStorm and Docker. I haven’t installed PHP or Composer locally. Next I want to learn how to use this new environment. This is what I have found out so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pop OS new install</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/10/05/Pop-OS-new-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 20:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/10/05/Pop-OS-new-install/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to test out Linux after I had purchased a new laptop which came with Windows 10 home. Although I was generally happy with my dev environment, I still wanted to try out Linux as a dev environment. I chose to try Pop OS as it was recommended by several people, especially on the PHPUgly and Syntax podcasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I enjoy coding Kata&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/08/05/Why-I-enjoy-coding-Katas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 21:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/08/05/Why-I-enjoy-coding-Katas/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that have helped me to learn software development using PHP is coding Katas. I especially enjoyed the Katas by Emily Bache on Github. They offer a safe sandbox environment to play with code and tools. They have good, or should that be not so good, starting code to self-teach techniques for refactoring, testing and object orientated code. In fact, I enjoyed them so much, I have contributed to them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup a new SilverStripe 4 Project</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/08/02/Setup-a-new-SilverStripe-4-Project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 12:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/08/02/Setup-a-new-SilverStripe-4-Project/</guid>
      <description>I have recently started a new job as a software developer, the tech stack includes a content management system (CMS) called Silverstripe. I therefore wanted to learn the Silverstripe CMS. The initial process of creating a project should be straight forward, there are supposed to be beginner lessons. The first three lessons on how to set up a silverstripe project are confusing, as there is intermixed talk about upgrading from Silverstripe v3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Docker on Windows 10 Home</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/07/02/Running-Docker-on-Windows-10-Home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 15:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/07/02/Running-Docker-on-Windows-10-Home/</guid>
      <description>I have recently purchased a new laptop with Windows 10 home edition, after some research I found out that Docker will now run on Windows 10 home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of Git and GitHub Learning Resources</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/06/01/List-of-git-Learning-Resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 19:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/06/01/List-of-git-Learning-Resources/</guid>
      <description>Some links from my recent learning about Git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standard Setup for PHP projects</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/06/01/Standard-Setup-for-PHP-Projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 23:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/06/01/Standard-Setup-for-PHP-Projects/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is my standard setup from 2020, a newer version from 2021 is now available Standard setup for PHP projects 2021. The focus of this post if to setup PHP and PhpStorm in a consistant way for each project, with coding standards, static analysis and tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating my GitHub.io website using Hexo</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/05/30/Creating-my-GitHub-io-website-using-Hexo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 17:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/05/30/Creating-my-GitHub-io-website-using-Hexo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in creating my own blog website for a while. I regularly create documentation in markdown and wanted an easy way to create a blog using markdown. This post explains my research and setup for Hexo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
