<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on Pen-y-Fan</title>
    <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on Pen-y-Fan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>:copyright: Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-SA 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 08:52:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pen-y-fan.github.io/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Standard setup for PHP projects 2021</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/05/23/Standard-setup-for-PHP-projects-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 08:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/05/23/Standard-setup-for-PHP-projects-2021/</guid>
      <description>The focus of this blog is to help set up PHP Projects in PhpStorm. I have also included snippets from my side-projects. I hope the information will be useful for other PHP projects. This is a follow-up to my blog Standard Setup for PHP projects from 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Docker</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/02/12/Troubleshooting-Docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 20:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/02/12/Troubleshooting-Docker/</guid>
      <description>I have been using Docker since I installed Pop!_OS On my laptop Oct 2020. I deliberately have not installed PHP, MySQL or Apache on my laptop, which has forced me to learn to use Docker! The first tutorial I followed was the Docker docs get started after I installed Docker. I found this to be a useful introduction, even though I wanted a PHP environment, the guide still explained the basics of Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up PhpStorm to use PHP with PHPUnit and xDebug in Docker</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/10/10/Set-up-PhpStorm-to-use-PHP-with-PHPUnit-and-xDebug-in-Docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 17:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/10/10/Set-up-PhpStorm-to-use-PHP-with-PHPUnit-and-xDebug-in-Docker/</guid>
      <description>I have recently configured my windows 10 laptop with an additional SSD, so I could experiment with Linux. I have already installed Pop!_OS Git, PhpStorm and Docker. I haven’t installed PHP or Composer locally. Next I want to learn how to use this new environment. This is what I have found out so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pop OS new install</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/10/05/Pop-OS-new-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 20:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/10/05/Pop-OS-new-install/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to test out Linux after I had purchased a new laptop which came with Windows 10 home. Although I was generally happy with my dev environment, I still wanted to try out Linux as a dev environment. I chose to try Pop OS as it was recommended by several people, especially on the PHPUgly and Syntax podcasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Docker on Windows 10 Home</title>
      <link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/07/02/Running-Docker-on-Windows-10-Home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 15:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/07/02/Running-Docker-on-Windows-10-Home/</guid>
      <description>I have recently purchased a new laptop with Windows 10 home edition, after some research I found out that Docker will now run on Windows 10 home.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
