<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PHP on Pen-y-Fan</title><link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/tags/php/</link><description>Recent content in PHP on Pen-y-Fan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>:copyright: Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-SA 4.0)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 10:19:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pen-y-fan.github.io/tags/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to set up Laragon on a new Windows computer (part 4) - Enable security</title><link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/11/10/how-to-set-up-laragon-on-a-new-windows-computer-part-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 10:19:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/11/10/how-to-set-up-laragon-on-a-new-windows-computer-part-4/</guid><description>When developing projects the development environment should be as close as possible to the production one. We can and should enable security</description></item><item><title>How to set up Laragon on a new Windows computer (part 3) - System tray icon</title><link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/11/08/how-to-set-up-laragon-on-a-new-windows-computer-part-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 11:46:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/11/08/how-to-set-up-laragon-on-a-new-windows-computer-part-3/</guid><description>Keeping the Laragon icon visible in the system tray, when minimised is helpful. In particular, it will avoid opening a new instance when one is already running.</description></item><item><title>My developer content recommendations</title><link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/08/21/my-developer-content-recommendations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 19:18:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2022/08/21/my-developer-content-recommendations/</guid><description>This is my curated and opinionated list on how I try to keep up to date with what&amp;rsquo;s going on in software development and in particular PHP.</description></item><item><title>How to send Emails using PHPMailer from Windows</title><link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/09/14/How-to-send-Emails-using-PHPMailer-from-Windows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 19:44:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/09/14/How-to-send-Emails-using-PHPMailer-from-Windows/</guid><description>This is a basic tutorial on how to send emails from Windows using PHPMailer.</description></item><item><title>How to Set up VS Code to use PHP with Xdebug 3 on Windows</title><link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/08/03/How-to-Set-up-VS-Code-to-use-PHP-with-Xdebug-3-on-Windows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 22:57:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/08/03/How-to-Set-up-VS-Code-to-use-PHP-with-Xdebug-3-on-Windows/</guid><description>VS Code with PHP and Xdebug 3 Xdebug 3 is an extremely powerful debugging tool for PHP. Although print_r(), var_dump() and dd() have their uses, Xdebug gives more powerful debugging options: step debugging allows the ability to view execution of each line of code, including the ability to view all variables and their values. Code coverage is useful to identify untested code, or code which is never executed (dead code).</description></item><item><title>Standard setup for PHP projects 2021</title><link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/05/23/Standard-setup-for-PHP-projects-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 08:52:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2021/05/23/Standard-setup-for-PHP-projects-2021/</guid><description>The focus of this blog is to help set up PHP Projects in PhpStorm. I have also included snippets from my side-projects. I hope the information will be useful for other PHP projects. This is a follow-up to my blog Standard Setup for PHP projects from 2020.</description></item><item><title>Set up PhpStorm to use PHP with PHPUnit and xDebug in Docker</title><link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/10/10/Set-up-PhpStorm-to-use-PHP-with-PHPUnit-and-xDebug-in-Docker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 17:01:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/10/10/Set-up-PhpStorm-to-use-PHP-with-PHPUnit-and-xDebug-in-Docker/</guid><description>I have recently configured my windows 10 laptop with an additional SSD, so I could experiment with Linux. I have already installed Pop!_OS Git, PhpStorm and Docker. I haven’t installed PHP or Composer locally. Next I want to learn how to use this new environment. This is what I have found out so far.</description></item><item><title>Why I enjoy coding Kata's</title><link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/08/05/Why-I-enjoy-coding-Katas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 21:30:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/08/05/Why-I-enjoy-coding-Katas/</guid><description>One of the things that have helped me to learn software development using PHP is coding Katas. I especially enjoyed the Katas by Emily Bache on Github. They offer a safe sandbox environment to play with code and tools. They have good, or should that be not so good, starting code to self-teach techniques for refactoring, testing and object orientated code. In fact, I enjoyed them so much, I have contributed to them!</description></item><item><title>Setup a new SilverStripe 4 Project</title><link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/08/02/Setup-a-new-SilverStripe-4-Project/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 12:59:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/08/02/Setup-a-new-SilverStripe-4-Project/</guid><description>I have recently started a new job as a software developer, the tech stack includes a content management system (CMS) called Silverstripe. I therefore wanted to learn the Silverstripe CMS. The initial process of creating a project should be straight forward, there are supposed to be beginner lessons. The first three lessons on how to set up a silverstripe project are confusing, as there is intermixed talk about upgrading from Silverstripe v3.</description></item><item><title>Standard Setup for PHP projects</title><link>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/06/01/Standard-Setup-for-PHP-Projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 23:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pen-y-fan.github.io/2020/06/01/Standard-Setup-for-PHP-Projects/</guid><description>Note: This is my standard setup from 2020, a newer version from 2021 is now available Standard setup for PHP projects 2021. The focus of this post if to setup PHP and PhpStorm in a consistant way for each project, with coding standards, static analysis and tests.</description></item></channel></rss>